III' PAUL RIPLEY

CONTACT

10258 Carmine Drive | Noblesville, IN 46060 317.509.5457 paulripley@hotmail.com www.paulripley.com

SUMMARY

I have been employed full-time as a user interface designer for a little over 20 years now. My projects have included graphic design, wireframe design, UX/UI design and layout, and front-end development.

Outside of my full-time positions, I have also taken on numerous freelance jobs doing website and logo design.

EXPERIENCE

Sallie Mae, Inc.

(July 2000 – Present) Fishers, IN 46238

Front-End Developer

(September 2015 – Present)

Responsible for designing and maintaining Sallie Mae's marketing site and customer servicing web app. Main tasks included:

- · Development of HTML components and CSS styling.
- Maintained close collaboration with creative team to ensure page layouts adhered to visual mockups and CSS styling matched style guide.
- · Created numerous cross-sell ad campaigns on customer servicing app to promote Sallie Mae products.

Project highlights include redesign of salliemae.com and maintenance of styling and components for Sallie Mae's Online Loan Servicing (OLS) customer servicing app.

Senior UX / UI Designer

(June 2010 – September 2015)

Responsible for user-experience design and strategy of Salliemae's various websites and applications. Main tasks included:

- · Discussing business requirements with project stakeholders.
- · Conducting research and competitor analysis to improve information architecture.
- Creating detailed site maps and wireframes that serve as the blueprint for visual design and content creation.

Project highlights include leading the redesign of Sallie Mae's Tuition Payment Plan website.

UI Designer

(July 2004 - June 2010)

Responsible for the design, development, and maintainence of websites, product demos, and web-based training programs for Sallie Mae's internal and external customers, primarily USA Funds, a Sallie Mae affiliate.

Main tasks included:

- Supporting the online marketing of USA Funds and its subsidiaries.
- Design and development of product demos for training and sales.
- Creating web-based training programs for financial-aid officers.

Project highlights include designing a new layout for USA Funds Connection, a customized Web portal for USA Funds school customers, developing and maintaining USA Funds' web-based loan counseling programs, and developing Flash-based games and quizzes for USA Funds University, a service that offers online-learning courses to education lending professionals.

Web Designer

(July 2000 - July 2004)

As a part of the online content team within the E-Commerce department, I was responsible for many tasks, which included the following:

- · Maintenance of all websites for Sallie Mae and its subsidiaries.
- · Design and development of new interface prototypes for various websites and applications.
- Graphic design and image enhancement of all brand elements included on Sallie Mae's websites.

Some of the more important projects included designing and developing an intranet for Sallie Mae, creating a prototype for a new loan consolidation application, developing interfaces for HTML emails, creating a Flash minisite for the new Sallie Mae headquarters, and redesigning Sallie Mae's sales resource website.

USA Group

(June 1999 - July 2000) Indianapolis, IN 46225

Electronic Graphic Specialist

Responsible for the design and development of USA Group's website, designing ad campaigns, and constructing brand elements.

EDUCATION Purdue University

W. Lafayette, IN 47906

Bachelor of Science in Computer Graphics Technology (received 1999)

Associate Degree in Technical Graphics (received 1997)

SKILLS Applications: Photoshop, Illustrator

Programming: HTML, XML, CSS, JavaScript

Personal: Professional, leader, self-reliant, highly motivated, eager to learn, team player, confident